<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clinton's blog</title><link>http://clintonbradford.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://clintonbradford.com/feeds/loncapa.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 02:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Initial LonCapa Thoughts</title><link>http://clintonbradford.com/posts/2017/06/loncapa-initial/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, Purdue University transitioned some math classes to a new instance of LonCapa. In the spring of 2017, I was assigned to adapt content for LonCapa as a half-time teaching position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a complicated relationship with the LonCapa project. Philosophically, a free-as-in-free-speech alternative to commercial softwares such as WebAssign, which we still use for several classes, appeals to me. High student fees, corporate-owned and controlled content, and the frequent outages we experienced all made me hope there was a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LonCapa, however, suffers from a number of issues that make it incredibly frustrating to work with. Poor documentation, coupled with a strange, locked-down old version of Perl, can make development cumbersome. (I just learned of the &amp;quot;allow&amp;quot; tag.) Frequent violations of best practice - or even on some occasions basic principles of web safety - make the dated interface seem like the least of our concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete lack of any asynchronous functionality means that students and instructors have to frequently reload, which is especially notable on problems which use complicated javascript-based content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I feel like the flexibility of a platform like this is worth the risks. Several other, similar softwares exist - I am particularly excited by edX, but haven't myself done much research - but even within the LonCapa framework, we can link together Geogebra Applets, external resources, and problem systems of our own design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to see what I can make using the available technology, and in what ways we can use the new technology to teach students better or more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Clinton Bradford</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 02:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:clintonbradford.com,2017-06-04:posts/2017/06/loncapa-initial/</guid><category>purdue</category><category>loncapa</category></item></channel></rss>