<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clinton's blog</title><link>http://clintonbradford.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://clintonbradford.com/feeds/seshet.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 02:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why I started seshet</title><link>http://clintonbradford.com/posts/2017/06/seshet-initial/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the strengths of WebAssign over LonCapa is the mathpad/calcpad/chempad/equationpad WYSIWYG (what-you-see-is-what-you-get) input system. Many students do not know intuitively how to translate an equation in text back and forth between the symbols they may use on paper, and in this switch to LonCapa we are taking them out of that comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to make a free, open-source WYSIWYG system, currently named Seshet (after the egyptian godess of mathematics and writing). I hope to build something that the students can more intutitvely use to answer questions and solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick MVP was up and running in a few days, displaying fractions, but doing something right the first time is harder and I hope to explain my thought process in a series of posts on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system will be hosted in &lt;cite&gt;a project on Github&lt;/cite&gt; and development will be tracked &lt;cite&gt;in a trello board&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the MVP used simple joining and separating of text inputs, the true project will keep a tree of javascript objects to hold the values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next post, I will explain the decisions behind that tree - and its three base classes - and hope to break down the basic structure for an exercise like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Clinton Bradford</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 02:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:clintonbradford.com,2017-06-04:posts/2017/06/seshet-initial/</guid><category>seshet</category><category>dev</category><category>js</category><category>purdue</category><category>loncapa</category></item></channel></rss>